<html>
<title>Economics and science</title>
<body>
<h2>Overview</h2>
<p>To understand D&amp;C economy you need to know this:</p>
<ul>
	<li>Not every planet is good for you. Not every planet can
		make you a profit. Sometimes armies and treachery are not as good as
		cooperation.</li>
	<li>To lower corruption you need to train governors. Every next
		governor costs more, so you can't expand forever, but	you
		need productive capacity to dominate.</li>
	<li>The wisest way to build an empire is to gather vassals. They will
		provide you with fleets, resources, money and, most important,
		they will grow your technology more than you would ever
		get alone.</li>
</ul>
<p>Now you know it. let's get a bit of details.</p>
<h2>Details</h2>
<p><strong>Money and resources</strong>.
Every your planet will produce resources. The amount of resources you get depend
on planet's natural resources, population and special bonus
buildings. Moneys depend on population and mined resources. The more
population you have and the more resources they gather, the more money
they will produce.</p>
<p><strong>Production</strong>. Production is similar to mining – it
depends on population and special “bonus” buildings.</p>
<p><strong>Science</strong>. Your science depends on amount of money you
get per turn. The more you get money from your planets, the higher your
tech level. Lose your money – you will use hand-axes, no matter how
cool you was.</p>
<p><strong>Science-II</strong>. Your planets can grow you tech level, yes.
But money from your vassals will grow your tech level <strong>five times faster</strong>.
One credit from your vassal is equal to few (depended on number of his governors) credits from your own planet!
Keeping in mind your inability to endlessly expand, this is the
reason, why you should develop your vassals network to dominate.</p>

<p><strong>Governors</strong>. Governors lowers corruption on the nearby
planets. Nearby does not mean the planet must be physically close,
this means that the closest to the governor planet will be affected most, then goes the next
planet and so on. About 7-th planet in this list will be corrupted
beyond all reason, no matter is the planet 20 or 5 squares away.</p>
</body>
</html>
