<html>
	<title>Making war</title>
<body>
<h2>Overview</h2>
<p>All you really need to know is this:</p>
<ul>
	<li>The more units you have the better</li>
	<li>The higher level your units have the better</li>
	<li>Units fire in predefined order, and depending on whether you are attacking or
		defending, order will start from light attackers or light defenders
		and end with heaviest defenders or attackers respectively.</li>
	<li>Mixed forces are often most effective.</li>
	<li>Battle may continue several turns. If you are losing a battle, run before
		it is too late.</li>
</ul>
<p>Following text covers most of battle calculation details. While this
details are quite important, you can still skip this boring treatise and
return here after you have played D&amp;C at least a week.</p>
<h2>Unit types. Unit properties.</h2>
<p>All battles can have two stages: space battle, if it is requested
and there is an enemy, and surface, if invasion was requested. This means
some units (like Shuttle) will fight twice  first in the space and then
on surface. All battles are calculated identically, no matter in space
or at a surface.</p>
<p>All units may have two kind of weapons  rockets or lasers.
They also have two independent defense systems  from rockets
and from lasers. Level 5 laser will hit unit with level 5 antilaser defense
with about 60% chance. Level 20 laser will hit level 5 defense with
about 100% chance, as well as 5-to-20 shot will have close to zero chance to hit.</p>
<p>In addition to attack rating all weapons have damage level. Rockets have
higher damage, but it is really hard to hit some units (like infantry or a fighter)
with them because of a good antirocket defense. If your technology allows you,
you can destroy enemy fighters with single shot, but if your enemy has close to
yours tech level, some units will be invulnerable for your rockets.</p>
<p>Every unit also has those "hitpoints", and when unit's hitpoints are equal
to zero this unit is equated to zero as well. If you have a carrier with 1%
hitpoints left, it is time to move it to one of your worlds, where damaged unit will
be automatically repaired.</p>
<p>Depending on the race you have chosen, your units can be stronger or weaker
from the start. Next important thing is "level". If you have high technology level,
all the units you create will be stronger then the base prototype.<!-- After the
battles, survivor's level will slowly grow too.--></p>
<p>From level to level unit's stats grow dramatically and two-level
gap between you and your opponent could mean he has a double
force with the same unit count and weight.</p>

<h2>Battles</h2>
<p>All fleet moves end <strong>BEFORE</strong> the battles are
calculated. All planet's production and support costs are calculated <strong>AFTER</strong>
 the battles are calculated. Battle starts when one fleet attacks another. Enemy's fleets can
remain in one system forever and never fight if they do not get an order to attack.</p>
<p>Once you are involved in the battle, <strong>ALL</strong> your fleets in the
system will fight. You will fight if you are attacking, if you were attacked or
if one of your fleets has an order to help an ally attacked or attacking. Ally relations are not
inherited, so you will not fight, if your ally will fight to help his ally.</p>
<p>If you are not attacking and you are not attacked and you have no
intent to help an ally, you are not involved in battle. If you allies fight with
each other, you are not fighting at all too.</p>
<p>After all fleets were moved, every fleet checks, if there are a targets it must attack
nearby. If there are  it does attack and it's fighting in attack order. Suppose you
have assembled a "Mad" fleet, order it to attack all vassals and moved it to
some vassal's planet. Fleet will arrive and attack all the vassal fleets it will
find. Your "Mad" fleet will go in attack order, while your vassals fleets will
be in defense order, even if they will expect you and order to attack a lord  arriving
fleet has a preference in attack.</p>
<p>Now when base order is defined for both players, units start firing at each other
one-by-one (or one-by-two, depending on the number of units you have). First go
light units, then heavy. Your bombers will crack vassals carriers, while
vassal's fighters will start to hunt for your bombers, and at the end of the
battle-turn your heavy ships will fire too.</p>
<p>Every unit has his own list of targets, like bombers will first attack
heavy jumpships while fighters will attack bombers. You can manually
define a "Mission" for one of your fleets, like "Destroy carriers", and
that fleet will do as you ask, all units will target selected unit class.</p>
<p>Inside of the target class, the target is chosen randomly.</p>
<p>This whole order thing will happen several times (currently, 5) and then stop.
Keep in mind, that your bombers will launch all rockets and can became a low-end
fighter after two battle-turns. Then all your transports and carriers are checked
to find units without a transport. All homeless units are killed, others will
be resorted among free space in your fleets, if needed. If you are fighting
on your own planet, all "lost units" are simply moved to garrison.</p>


</body>
</html>
