<html>
	<title>FAQ</title>
<body>
<h2>NOTE: During testing period ALL game features are free.</h2>

<p><strong>Q: My account seems to be removed, what's going on? I've registered half a year ago
and returned today to spend all the resources collected. But I can not login!</strong></p>
<p><strong>A:</strong> To keep universe clean of zombies, free accounts are periodically removed using the following rules:</p>
<p>Players, who haven't choose a planet, are removed in 2 days.</p>
<p>Players, not logged in after the registration during the next 5 days, are removed</p>
<p>Players, who did not login for two month, are removed.</p>
<p>Players, who's last login time is older, than period between registration and last login, are removed.</p>
<p>In short you should login at least once a week or purchase a premium account.</p>


<p><strong>Q: I have an excess of money over here, can I make my game
experience better?</strong></p>
<p><strong>A:</strong> Yes, you can. First if all, you can buy a premium account.
This will let you to login at any time, no matter how many players are currently
on-line, get copies of selected game messages to your e-mail and get some other sweet
improvements. Then you can purchase a right to have an unique avatar, an icon for your
planets or even for the whole your empire. You can even purchase a right to
create your own custom race.</p>

<p><strong>Q: Can I buy something MORE usable? Like a planet or unit? Can I
at least buy resources? Or buy a race with balance shifted? Or scalps of my enemies?</strong></p>
<p><strong>A:</strong> No, you can not buy that. All resources in the game must be
created inside it. There is no way to import real money into the game. Period.<br/>
<strong>BUT</strong>. What you <strong>can</strong> do is to buy something from other players.
You can even purchase a fully assembled empire, if someone will sell it to you. While we seriously doubt
such kind of playing is in at any way enjoyable.</p>

</body>
</html>