<html>
	<overtitle>Quick start</overtitle>
	<subtitle>Choosing a race</subtitle>
<body>
<p>So, you are starting your game. Let's assume you can select a user name and a password without
reading a manual, but
now you have to choose a race. Here is a place a manual could be handy.</p>

<img src="/static/manual/racechoose1_en.gif" alt="" width="314" height="272" vspace="30" hspace="10" border="0"/>
<p>We will start from a predefined race. Later we will use it as it is or rebuild it to meet our
requirements.</p>
<p>Let us start with “Humans”, the most famous race on the Earth.</p>
<img src="/static/manual/racechoose2_en.gif" alt="" width="361" height="792" vspace="30" hspace="10" border="0"/>
<p>Well, what have we got here? We have a lime mark near the base race properties – race nature and
production nature. Human's nature is organic, everybody knows that already. To survive
human consumes proteins and carbohydrates.</p>
<p>But what else should we know? We should know that on the planet with lots of organics humans
multiply faster. Population growth speed can reach 4% or more on a planet
rich with organics. The planet without organics, thou, will have zero population growth speed.</p>
<p>Population will be your most valuable resource. The more you population is, the more
resources they gather and the more money they will produce. And buildings/units production speed
depends on the population size as well.</p>
<p>Human's industry is based on minerals, like iron ore, oil, coal and the like. That's not a sensation again.
To support the industry humans mine and then spend minerals to produce buildings, spaceships and
other funny stuff. The more minerals on the planet are, the more humans will mine and the more units they
will be able to produce and/or support. Planet with minerals but without organics, unfortunately,
is forbidden for humans – they will not be able to multiply enough to actually mine something useful.</p>

<p>In fact, there are <strong>three</strong> resources in the game – <span class="m">M</span>inerals, <span class="o">O</span>rganics and <span class="e">E</span>nergy.
We know about all, but energy. Do humans use energy?</p>
<p>Of course they do. Not that they do it right, but they are trying hard. As the result, they
do mine energy, but exactly half as good as they mine minerals with other things being equal. This means
humans will have to take care about the energy too, while they will not use it much.</p>

<p>Ok, now we know some worlds are unusable for humans because of the low organics concentration and
some are unusable because of the lack of the minerals and the energy. What
good news are still waiting for us?</p>
<p>Marked with red graph on the screenshot above is still waiting. This graph describes weather our colonists will
live or die on the planet depending on it's temperature.</p>
<p>As we can see, our human colonists are fine while surface temperature is somewhat between
5 and 35 degrees centigrade. The more we deviate from that range the worse our colonists
survive and on the planets with surface temperature above 50° our colonists will start
do die out, no matter how many organics they can find around.</p>
<p>In D&amp;C universe planets can have temperature in 0°-99° range, so humans are reasonably comfortable
on every third planet. Not bad at all, by the way.</p>
<p>Next goes marked with blue base race parameters. This is what you can change when you create your
custom race. Below you can find marked with orange derivative race stats. This race
properties are calculated using a dedicated formula from the base parameters.</p>
<p>This therewith means you can not simply, say, make you ships fly far and fast. Instead you will
have to make you race nomads and get in addition to good fly speed slow
civil production, altered mining rate and other, not always desired, shifts.</p>

<p>Let us suppose we are not satisfied with Humans race. Retarded scientists,
decrepit units and other unpleasant things make us press “Customize race...” button.
We will make our ships fast and our peoples strong.</p>
<p>What we see in the next window looks mostly common for us. But the bottom of the page is different,
here we can see our race constructor window.</p>

<img src="/static/manual/racechoose3_en.gif" alt="" width="273" height="458" vspace="30" hspace="10" border="0"/>
<p>Now we have all the controls in our hands and can really create something cool. You can change your race
nature and industry nature. You can set comfortable temperature for your race. You can manipulate
with base race parameters. I am going to produce “Vorlon” race. Those who have seeing “Babylon 5” series must remember
it was an ancient and powerful, but dying out race of something we can assume to be energy nature.</p>
<p>Let's start constructing. Race nature – energy, production nature – organics (they’ve taught
some other race to grow alive ships or something like that, if memory serves me well). This is an ancient
race of bores. Something like this, I believe:</p>

<img src="/static/manual/racechoose4_en.gif" alt="" width="273" height="458" vspace="30" hspace="10" border="0"/>
<p>Click “Update” and see the result:</p>
<img src="/static/manual/racechoose5_en.gif" alt="" width="361" height="762" vspace="30" hspace="10" border="0"/>
<p>Not that this race is bad or is completely unlike it's prototype, but it is definitely not as
powerful as the prototype was in the series. We will have to take it the way it is – game does not allow
us to get something for free.</p>
<p>All right, we like our Vorlonians for any way and we press “Take this race”. Now we see a list of
the available homeworlds.</p>
<img src="/static/manual/racechoose6_en.gif" alt="" width="314" height="231" vspace="30" hspace="10" border="0"/>
<p>Now we have to decide where will be our homeworld. We could start from the universe center, find there
a powerful patron and grow in a peaceful environment. In other hand we can find ourselves at a border world,
fighting with both (or more) sides.</p>
<p>Alternatively we can land far from the center and try our luck in making our own empire
from the scratch. Or in surviving endless conflicts with
neighbors.</p>
<p>Or we can just ignore all this matters and choose the best planet game offers. In fact it is
not really a perfect idea as well because good planets nearby are much more important for any way, but
we must start somewhere, after all.</p>

<p>Planet notation in the list is quite simple and you should read it like this:<br/>
X:Y; Temperature: ##, Surface: ##, Organics: ##, Energy: ##, Minerals: ##.</p>
<p>First go planet coordinates, than planet conditions. then resources, marked as
O (Organics), E (Energy), M (Minerals). This notation, as well as the color notation
<span class="o">O</span>,
<span class="e">E</span>, <span class="m">M</span>, is used in the game everywhere, so you should
remember and recognize it.</p>
<p>Now let's check what is offered to us:</p>

<img src="/static/manual/racechoose7_en.gif" alt="" width="314" height="468" vspace="30" hspace="10" border="0"/>
<p>Most attractable planets are marked, and the best planet is definitely 549:547. It is large – it will
fit large population to produce lots of resources and build units faster. It has high concentration
of organics. With minerals things are not so fine, bit this planet seems to be the best out there.</p>
<p>We choose 549:547 and press “Ok”.</p>
<p>Alea jacta est. <a href="/en/about/guide_ii/">Next part</a> of this guide will teach us to
construct buildings, mine resources and plan our expansion.</p>
<br/>
<p><a href="/en/about/guide_ii/">Go to the next part &gt;&gt;</a></p>
</body>
</html>