<html>
	<subtitle>Mining, constructing</subtitle>
<body>

<p>From the <a href="/en/about/guide/">previous part</a> of this guide we know how to choose
a race and a planet. Now when the planet is chosen we will learn to survive in the game universe.</p>
<p>We open “Planet” tab and see something like this:</p>

<img src="/static/manual/play1_en.gif" alt="" width="501" height="390" vspace="30" hspace="10" border="0"/>
<p>First thing to note is marked with green you resources fund. To build something in the game
you will have to have resources, and here you can see how much resources you have. Our
“Vorlon” race utilizes organics and minerals for industry purposes, so that resources
are shown. Energy is completely eaten by vorlonians during breakfasts and lunches and
could not be collected at all. Humans will eat organics and have minerals and
energy as a resources. Last indicators shows the money you have.</p>

<table>
<tr>
	<td><img src="/static/manual/play2.gif" alt="" width="382" height="28" vspace="30" hspace="10" border="0"/></td>
	<td>“Vorlon” resources</td>
</tr>
<tr>
	<td><img src="/static/manual/play3.gif" alt="" width="382" height="28" vspace="30" hspace="10" border="0"/></td>
	<td>“Humans” resources</td>
</tr>
</table>
<p>For every resource you can see how much is currently available, how much was produced and spent during
the last turn. We have not survived a single turn yet so there are zeroes. This numbers will
show you how much was <strong>really</strong> produced and spend, with respect to all roundings made.</p>
<p>Now we will look at marked with yellow buildings list. It shows us all the buildings we already
have on the planet and what buildings we can already create. All units are created here as well, not only
buildings. Every existing building has a short description and support costs (marked with red).</p>
<img src="/static/manual/play4_en.gif" alt="" width="318" height="336" vspace="30" hspace="10" border="0"/>
<p>Note the already known for us resource color/letter notation <span style="color: lime;">O</span> (Organics),
<span style="color:#00ffff;">E</span> (Energy), <span style="color: Red;">M</span> (Minerals).</p>
<p>We can see that our shipyard consumes seven points of organics and four of minerals. All theis numbers are rounded and after the turn calculations you may get slightly
different numbers on the top of the screen.</p>
<p>Every mining building has it's mining capabilities described (green marker on the picture).</p>
<p>Blue marker shows we can easily destroy anything we have built. To save money on support, for example.</p>
<p>Now let us scroll down to see available buildings list.</p>

<table>
<tr>
	<td>“Vorlon”</td>
	<td>“Humans”</td>
</tr>
<tr>
	<td><img src="/static/manual/play7_en.gif" alt="" width="318" height="336" vspace="30" hspace="10" border="0"/></td>
	<td><img src="/static/manual/play6_en.gif" alt="" width="318" height="336" vspace="30" hspace="10" border="0"/></td>
</tr>
</table>
<p>Note the different prices for different races.</p>
<p>We again see well-known resources, but we also see two new notations.
<span style="color: yellow;">C</span> (Credits) is quite transparent.
<span style="color:#ff00ff;">P</span> (People) shows amount of people
a building will employ. To create a building you must have enough free people
on the planet. This means you can not endlessly build, say, mines on the planet - 
once all peoples are busy, no people-requiring buildings can be created on it.</p>
<p>Purple mark brings our attention to the difference in creation time for civil and military buildings.
While shuttle takes the same six turns to complete, colony creation will be noticeably longer for humans.</p>

<p>“[build]” link's purpose is clear, so we go ahead and start constructing biofarm.</p>
<img src="/static/manual/play5_en.gif" alt="" width="318" height="336" vspace="30" hspace="10" border="0"/>
<p>Now in the building queue we see our in-progress-farm and our resources at the top
of the page had decreased.</p>
<p>If we will “[cancel]” our biofarm all resources will be returned to us. If we cancel our
farm later all resources will be restored as well and moreover, all the job progress will be
transferred to the next building in the queue, if any. This means canceling production is a
completely safe and free action. Unlike action “disband”, which will return you <strong>nothing</strong>.</p>
<p>You can fill queue as long as you have enough resources to order something. As soon
as the planet will finish one building, it will start constructing the next one. The only
limitation is the number of completed buildings per turn - <strong>one</strong>.</p>
<p>Production speed depends on the planet population, race bonuses, building type (civil/military) and
can be increased with buildings like “Factory”.</p>

<br/>
<p>Well, spending money is more or less clear. Now it is time to understand where do our
money come from. The window inside the red marker is the one we need.</p>
<img src="/static/manual/play8_en.gif" alt="" width="318" height="336" vspace="30" hspace="10" border="0"/>
<p>Green line marks planet properties. Being familiar with the game notations you must recognize
the meaning of this graph, but we will explain it one more time. Left to right there are:
Organics concentration, Energy concentration, Minerals concentration, surface Temperature,
planet Surface. Every parameter may vary between 1 and 99.</p>
<p>For the “Average” race (all base properties are 50, no bonuses) with organics nature and mineral
industry the planet of the size 50 with the perfect temperature and 50 of every resource, 50&#160;000
population anв no mining buildings will do like this:</p>

<br/>
<table border="1" cellpadding="3" cellspacing="0">
<tr>
	<th>Parameter</th>
	<th>Formulation</th>
	<th>Result</th>
</tr>
<tr>
	<td>Main resource</td>
	<td>50000<span class="p">P</span>*50<span class="m">М</span>/<span style="color: #CECA6F;">160000</span></td>
	<td align="right">15<span class="m">М</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
	<td>Secondary resource</td>
	<td>50000<span class="p">P</span>*50<span class="e">E</span>/<span style="color: #CECA6F;">160000</span>/2</td>
	<td align="right">7<span class="e">E</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
	<td>Money</td>
	<td><nobr>50000<span class="p">P</span>/<span style="color: #CECA6F;">25000</span> + (15<span class="m">М</span>+7<span class="e">E</span>)/<span style="color: #CECA6F;">5</span></nobr></td>
	<td align="right">6<span class="c">C</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
	<td>Science</td>
	<td>6<span class="c">C</span>*<span style="color: #CECA6F;">1</span></td>
	<td align="right">6</td>
</tr>
<tr>
	<td>Population growth</td>
	<td>50<span class="o">O</span>*<span style="color: #CECA6F;">0,05</span></td>
	<td align="right">2%</td>
</tr>
<tr>
	<td>Ьan-hourы per turn</td>
	<td>50000<span class="p">P</span>*<span style="color: #CECA6F;">0,01</span></td>
	<td align="right">500</td>
</tr>
<tr>
	<td>Population limit</td>
	<td>50<span class="s">S</span>*<span style="color: #CECA6F;">2000</span></td>
	<td align="right">100000<span class="p">P</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
	<td colspan="3"><small><span style="color: #CECA6F;">Gold</span> color marks constants which are a subject
	to change. In money calculation (15<span class="m">М</span>+7<span class="e">E</span>) means a summ of
	main and secondary resources production.</small></td>
</tr>
</table>
<br/>
<p>A race with 20% mining bonus will get<br/>
<code>50000<span class="p">P</span>*50<span class="m">М</span>/<span style="color: #CECA6F;">160000</span>*1.2=18<span class="m">М</span></code>
<br/>of the main resouce. Having population of 80&#160;000 on the same planet that race will have
<code>80000<span class="p">P</span>*50<span class="m">М</span>/<span style="color: #CECA6F;">160000</span>*1.2=28<span class="m">М</span></code>,<br/>
and adding two mines to this we will see<br/>
<code>80000<span class="p">P</span>*50<span class="m">М</span>/<span style="color: #CECA6F;">160000</span>*1.2*1.4=40<span class="m">М</span></code>.</p>
<p>As long as money depend on resources, money will grow as well.</p>
<p>Surface column (S) may confuse us - it us definitely split by two. The meaning of this is simple:
blue shows us overall surface, while crimson shows us the currently occupied part of the planet (95% in this case).</p>
<p>Now let us look at the table marked with yellow. This is information about our population too,
but from another point. Here we can see absolute population size, number of unemployed people and
the speed of the population growth.</p>
<p>Population growth speed depends on race bonuses, resource concentration (for vorlonians
energy concentration will affect population growth) and percent of the unused
surface. As soon as your population reaches 50% of the maximum possible,
population growth speed will slowly degrade and population will stabilize.</p>
<p>Building an energy generator we will increase vorlonian population growth speed by 20%.
For humans we would build biofarm for the same purpose.</p>

<p>Now let us try to land humans on the same planet.</p>
<table>
<tr>
	<td>“Vorlon”</td>
	<td>“Humans”</td>
</tr>
<tr>
	<td><img src="/static/manual/play8_en.gif" alt="" width="318" height="336" vspace="30" hspace="10" border="0"/></td>
	<td><img src="/static/manual/play9_en.gif" alt="" width="318" height="336" vspace="30" hspace="10" border="0"/></td>
</tr>
</table>
<p>Humans will slowly die out here, at the first place. The reason is surface temperature  - humans can
not leave on a planet with 52°.</p>
<p>Another important point - mining speed. Humans are good in mining. Vorlonians are good in fighting.</p>
<p>There is another, hard to detect, difference - humans occupy only 58% (vs 59% for Vorlon), they use surface slightly better.</p>
<p>Now let us once again take a look at the resources (red marker) and repeat what we know already.
The more resource concentration, the more we will mine. The bigger is population - the faster we will mine.
The more mining buildings we have on a planet, the faster the mining will be.</p>
<p>Money depend on resources and population.</p>
<p>Before this part will end, we will take a short look at the orange mark at the
first picture on this page. This mark surrounds events window. Every event in the game, like
building finished or alien fleet arrival will create an event in this window. Now this window contains
greeting, and this greeting, among the other things, contain an advise to create a fleet and
make our first hyperspace jump. <a href="/en/about/guide_iii/">Next part</a> will
tesch us to fly and explore.</p>

<br/>
<p><a href="/en/about/guide_iii/">Go to the next part &gt;&gt;</a></p>
</body>
</html>