<html>
	<subtitle>First hyperspace jump</subtitle>
<body>
<p>In the <a href="/en/about/guide_ii/">previous part</a> of this guide we have reviewed our homeworld
and ordered a new building (Biofarm). Now then we have a general knowlege of our home it is time
to explore the world around.</p>
<p>We open thep “Planet” tab again, but now we will work with other parts of the game interface.</p>
<img src="/static/manual/fly1_en.gif" alt="" width="500" height="387" vspace="30" hspace="10" border="0"/>
<p>Green marker brings our attention to the celestial map.</p>
<p>Planet in the center of the map is marked with white square, this is an active planet. Active
planet is always in the center of the map, and now it is our homeworld.</p>
<p>All around our homeworld we can see colored bolls pretending to be planets. Be warned:
<strong>planet color means nothing</strong>.</p>
<p><strong>Planet size is important</strong> - it allows you to approximate planet's surface size. As
you must remember from the previous part of this guide, population size affects production and mining speed
and thus is very important. Larger planet can hold a larger population.</p>
<p>Except for the approximate size of the planets nearby, our map contains no information so far. Time
to start exploring the area.</p>
<img src="/static/manual/fly2_en.gif" alt="" width="318" height="336" vspace="30" hspace="10" border="0"/>
<p>Important objects are marked with green. Most probably there are very few planets around our vorlonians cal leave on,
and finding a suitable large planet is an unlikely event, but we have to start somewhere, let's explore
large planets first.</p>
<p>Distances are very important in the game too. Flying over three cells can take as long as 20 turns
for some races and thus we should take a great care about the nearest planets first.</p>
<p>Another thing to keep in mind while starting exploration is a chance to find an alien planet,
being tracked and attacked. Yet we will not care of it for now.</p>
<p>So the first planet in our to-do list is a dark giant 548:546. Now let us take a closer look at our
scouting force. It is located in the “Space fleets” window, marked with red on the first picture.
There is a yellow color as well, it marks “Planet's Harrison” text. And there also is an extraordinary
important button of “Create a fleet” (blue arrow). Now we click “Planet's Harrison” text and see this:</p>
<img src="/static/manual/fly3_en.gif" alt="" width="318" height="336" vspace="30" hspace="10" border="0"/>
<p>Let us make an inspection of our Harrison.</p>
<p>Yellow marker shows us a quick info on our Harrison. There is
jumpships number, carrier-based units number, transportable items number. We do not seem to have any carrier-based units
so far.</p>
<p>What we do have is a probe (green mark). Quite a fast but hopelessly peaceful unit. This unit
(and only this unit) can explore a planet surface and tell us, what is the exact planet size, how many resources the planet
contains and how hot the planet's surface is.</p>
<p>Another usable thing about the probe is it's stealth engines.
Probe's engines are relatively weak and turning stealth on
takes money, but still. Perhaps, we already have an alien probe on our orbit tracking us down.</p>
<p>We have a shuttle as well, and reviewing it's description we can assume it is can do some transporting
as well as some fighting. Bringing a colony to the target planet will be a nice task for this peace
of metal.</p>
<p>And we do have two infantry units. Those brave kids with lasers in hand are the ones to
stop anyone trying to invade our home. Hopefully. Yet our vorlonians infantry is way stronger
than, say, humans infantry. Really stronger.</p>
<p>Well, the war is clearly an easy deal for us, let's get back to exploring. We are going to send a probe
to 548:546 system.</p>

<p>All hyperspace jumps in the game are made by <strong>fleets</strong>. You can not take a shuttle and
order it to fly and fight somewhere. No. First you create a fleet, then put your shuttle into it and
<strong>then</strong> order the whole thing to fly. Maybe you should add an infantry to the fleet before flying. Or a couple of more shuttles with infantry aboard. For any way, you will give an order to the
whole formation.</p>
<p>Note, that you can not bring, say, infantry to the fleet without transports. Infantry is unable to
survive on the orbit, no matter are they in a fleet or not.</p>
<img src="/static/manual/fly4_en.gif" alt="" width="318" height="336" vspace="30" hspace="10" border="0"/>
<p>For our exploration task one-probe fleet will be fine, so we create a fleet of “Scout” and open our
harrison again. Near to the units we can put in our fleet we see “Transfer to” drop-down.</p>
<img src="/static/manual/fly5_en.gif" alt="" width="318" height="336" vspace="30" hspace="10" border="0"/>
<p>Note once again - we are unable to move infantry.</p>
<p>Now we transfer our probe to the new fleet. We open drop-down list and choose our “Scout” fleet as
a target. Numbers in Harrison and fleet headers change.</p>
<img src="/static/manual/fly6_en.gif" alt="" width="318" height="336" vspace="30" hspace="10" border="0"/>
<p>There is a yellow-marked button “Make a fly to” and some information about our fleet.</p>
<p>Marked with aqua numbers in header mean: jumpship number, number of carrier-based units/number of carrier slots,
number of transportable items/number of transport pods. We have a single jumpship without any kind of
pods, it's a small probe. Note the number of jumpships in Harrison header - is now 1.</p>
<p>Red mark surrounds our fleet's jump engines quality. Our vorlonaans are not fast at all, we have
to admit. Speed is 0.4, maximum distance is 4.01.</p>
<p>Green color - stealth engines. Stealth engine quality is 1.6, it is not too good as well,
in fact. Moreover turning stealth on will require 61 credit plus 6 credits per turn.
I suppose it is too early to invest so much, let's preserve our money for a while.</p>
<p>There is marked with blue item “Change fleet behavior”, but we will deal with it later.
Unnecessary to give battle orders to our hopelessly peaceful fleet. Instead we press
“Make a fly to...” button and type in target coordinates 548:546. The colon we could replace with
dot or comma. We press Ok and our fleet disappears from the planet. Instead we see
a small white dot on the celestial map. We click on the 548:546 to activate the planet.</p>

<img src="/static/manual/fly7_en.gif" alt="" width="318" height="336" vspace="30" hspace="10" border="0"/>
<p>This huge green arrow shows a little dot on the map - our flying fleet representation. As soon as
our fleet will arrive, the dot will grow.</p>
<p>Let us check “Space fleets” window now. Disappeared from our homeworld fleet is now here. It's name
is grayed to show the fact the fleet is still in transit.</p>
<img src="/static/manual/fly8_en.gif" alt="" width="318" height="336" vspace="30" hspace="10" border="0"/>
<p>All the information about the fleet we can see now is remaining traveling time (green). And we can still
cancel a jump. When the turn will be calculated our fleet will enter hyperspace and we will be unable
to communicate with it at all, but now we still have full control over it.</p>
<p>Our first space journey will soon start and will last for four turns. Some races can
cross the same distance in two turns, but vorlon is slow, yes.</p>

<p>In the <a href="/en/about/guide_iv/">next part</a> we will explore the planets nearby,
meet with aliens and will try to establish our first colony.</p>

<p><a href="/en/about/guide_iv/">Go to the next part &gt;&gt;</a></p>
</body>
</html>