<html>
	<subtitle>Exploring, spying</subtitle>
<body>
<p>In the <a href="/en/about/guide_iii/">previous part</a> of the guide we have send our not-too-fast vorlonian fleet
to nearest to us giant planet.</p>
<p>Four turns had gone, on our homeworld biofarm was completed and we have ordered another one.
Population changed from 70&#160;000	to 74&#160;216.</p>
<p>And our “Scout” had reached it's target. We open
“Planet”, click on 548:546 and examine the screen.</p>

<img src="/static/manual/research1_en.gif" alt="" width="318" height="336" vspace="30" hspace="10" border="0"/>
<p>As was promised, white dot had grown to white dash and green arrow points to that dash.</p>
<p>Red arrow points to planet's occupation state. In fact there are two red arrows and they both point
to occupation markers. Markers are clearly different - our home world’s one
is white (our world) and is filled (world is occupied). Unfilled triangle
marks a free world and is always gray.</p>
<p>Below you can find all possible occupation icons.</p>

<table border="0" cellpadding="3" cellspacing="0">
<tr>
	<td colspan="2"><img src="http://info.the-game.ru/img/ico_dip_self.gif" width="11" height="11" alt="" border="0"/></td>
	<td>Your planet</td>
</tr>
<tr>
	<td><img src="http://info.the-game.ru/img/ico_dip_l.gif" width="11" height="11" alt="" border="0"/></td>
	<td><img src="http://info.the-game.ru/img/ico_dip_fl.gif" width="11" height="11" alt="" border="0"/></td>
	<td>Unoccupied planet</td>
</tr>
<tr>
	<td><img src="http://info.the-game.ru/img/ico_dip_00l.gif" width="11" height="11" alt="" border="0"/></td>
	<td><img src="http://info.the-game.ru/img/ico_dip_00fl.gif" width="11" height="11" alt="" border="0"/></td>
	<td>Occupied, no diplomatic relation set</td>
</tr>
<tr>
	<td><img src="http://info.the-game.ru/img/ico_dip_0l.gif" width="11" height="11" alt="" border="0"/></td>
	<td><img src="http://info.the-game.ru/img/ico_dip_0fl.gif" width="11" height="11" alt="" border="0"/></td>
	<td>Your enemy's world</td>
</tr>
<tr>
	<td><img src="http://info.the-game.ru/img/ico_dip_1l.gif" width="11" height="11" alt="" border="0"/></td>
	<td><img src="http://info.the-game.ru/img/ico_dip_1fl.gif" width="11" height="11" alt="" border="0"/></td>
	<td>Neytral</td>
</tr>
<tr>
	<td><img src="http://info.the-game.ru/img/ico_dip_2l.gif" width="11" height="11" alt="" border="0"/></td>
	<td><img src="http://info.the-game.ru/img/ico_dip_2fl.gif" width="11" height="11" alt="" border="0"/></td>
	<td>Ally</td>
</tr>
<tr>
	<td><img src="http://info.the-game.ru/img/ico_dip_3l.gif" width="11" height="11" alt="" border="0"/></td>
	<td><img src="http://info.the-game.ru/img/ico_dip_3fl.gif" width="11" height="11" alt="" border="0"/></td>
	<td>Vassal</td>
</tr>
<tr>
	<td><img src="http://info.the-game.ru/img/ico_dip_4l.gif" width="11" height="11" alt="" border="0"/></td>
	<td><img src="http://info.the-game.ru/img/ico_dip_4fl.gif" width="11" height="11" alt="" border="0"/></td>
	<td>Lord</td>
</tr>
</table>
<p>Marker may have or may have not a gray grid. This greed marks the worlds with posibbly outdated
state. Our Probe is here, so no grid present, but as soon as our probe leaves this world,
the outdated state will be set.</p>
<p><strong>Any fleet</strong> can see occupation state, no probe required. But we are here
with another mission - we want to know weather our vorlonians will leave here or die.</p>
<p>Next to our planet we can see a graph (blue arrow) while this planet has no such graph. That
what our probe will do - plot a graph and put it on our map.</p>
<p>We go back to “Space fleets” window, expand our “Scout” fleet and look at our probe.</p>

<img src="/static/manual/research2_en.gif" alt="" width="318" height="336" vspace="30" hspace="10" border="0"/>
<p>Here it is. Research will take one turn to complete and will cost us 98 credits. We click
“[Explore]” and wait a turn to end.</p>
<p>...single turn calculated...</p>
<p>Let us return to our scientists and see what they have done. They have done well.
We now have full information on this world (aqua arrow).</p>
<img src="/static/manual/research3.gif" alt="" width="286" height="286" vspace="30" hspace="10" border="0"/>
<p>One more thing we have is information what will happen with vorlonian on this planet.
Green arrow points to a red line, crossing our hope to colonize this world. If this line would
be pink, this would mean we could survive here. Yellow or orange line means we could leave here fine. 
Green line would mean a perfect conditions for our race. Red means our race will dye out here.</p>
<p>But there is something more our probe had found, There is an alien fleet approaching the planet.</p>
<p>Red arrow targets red dot. This is an alien fleet. We can not say who is fleet's owner
until it in the hyperspace, so all such fleets are marked red on the map.</p>
<p>Well, we know something is approaching. What else do we know? Let us look at
“Planet news” window.</p>
<img src="/static/manual/research4_en.gif" alt="" width="318" height="336" vspace="30" hspace="10" border="0"/>
<p>Now we know from where the fleet is flying. We know jumpships number. And we
know the weight of the fleet. The only jumpship with such weight is a probe.
The planet a probe started from has suspiciously average size, which could mean
it is someone's homeworld.</p>
<p>Now we have to decide what to do next. We can fly away now. This will save us
time and we will definitely not disclose our existence. That was pro. Contra is
we will not get any more information.</p>
<p>Another way is to turn stealth on and wait for our neighbor to arrive. This will
let us to know who is the neighbor and where he will fly next. Keeping in mind he can not
fly to an empty world, we could discover one more alien planet.</p>
<p>If we know our neighbor's name, we will be able to know his race, how long he is in the game,
what his game rating is, how many planets he has. Suppose his probe will leave to 550:543 instead of returning
to 549:544. If we would know he has two planets - we have his portrait in our pocket without even
being seeing.</p>
<p>The problem could arise if the neighbor has advanced detection capabilities and will
detect our hidden unit.</p>
<p>This is a guide, so I have to stay for any way. In the game you will decide for your self.</p>
<br/>
<p>One more thing to note is “Space fleets” window. There is our fleet and there is the allien fleet as well.</p>
<img src="/static/manual/research5_en.gif" alt="" width="318" height="336" vspace="30" hspace="10" border="0"/>
<p>This notation looks similar to the one we have seeing in our Harrison, but this numbers
have completely different meaning. This is not “Three jumpships, one carrier-based, one transportable”,
but it is “Three turns, one jumpship, one ton”. This is only a probe.</p>
<br/>
<p>To save 12 credits we will only turn stealth on when the aliens arrive.</p>

<p>...two turns calculated...</p>
<p>We turn stealth on</p>
<p>...single turn calculated...</p>
<p>That's it! We can see him now, he (hopefully) can not see us.</p>

<img src="/static/manual/research6_en.gif" alt="" width="318" height="336" vspace="30" hspace="10" border="0"/>
<p>This is human, and our warriors are definitely superior to humans. This fleet is called
“Researcher”, which is not too informative since we already know it is a probe. Notation changed again
(no turns till arrival now). Name of our neighbor is known to us as well, he has two planets
already. Let us wait a bit and see where he will fly next.</p>

<p>...two turns calculated...</p>
<p>Let us see.</p>
<img src="/static/manual/research7_en.gif" alt="" width="318" height="336" vspace="30" hspace="10" border="0"/>
<p>For any way that was cool. We know about his possible homeworld. Probably “Vorlon” race will
have a hard time searching for a world to land. But shake humans to get some resources should be an easy
task. Time to get profit from our race's strengths.</p>

<p>In the <a href="/en/about/guide_v/">next part</a> of this guide we will create an army and visit
our neighbor.</p>

<p><a href="/en/about/guide_v/">Go to the next part &gt;&gt;</a></p>
</body>
</html>